<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>https://aiko.dev/</id><title>Aiko Klostermann</title><subtitle>Aiko Klostermann: Software engineer, Keynote speaker, Technology Blog, Software Engineering</subtitle> <updated>2025-10-08T13:24:55+08:00</updated> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> <uri>https://aiko.dev/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://aiko.dev/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="" href="https://aiko.dev/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2025 Aiko Klostermann </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>[Talk] Demystifying LLMs: How to Use GenAI Effectively (to keep your job)</title><link href="https://aiko.dev/demystifying-llms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Talk] Demystifying LLMs: How to Use GenAI Effectively (to keep your job)" /><published>2025-10-08T00:00:00+08:00</published> <updated>2025-10-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated> <id>https://aiko.dev/demystifying-llms/</id> <content src="https://aiko.dev/demystifying-llms/" /> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> </author> <summary>Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT and Gemini are reshaping how people in every field approach problem-solving, from brainstorming ideas to debugging complex systems. This talk will explain, in straightforward terms, how LLMs work, what they’re good at, and where their boundaries lie. We’ll explore the principles of prompt engineering—how to frame questions and instructions ...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>[Talk] You don’t need to hire a 10x engineer, you just need to enable the engineers you have</title><link href="https://aiko.dev/no-10x-engineer-needed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Talk] You don’t need to hire a 10x engineer, you just need to enable the engineers you have" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+08:00</published> <updated>2024-12-19T12:54:37+08:00</updated> <id>https://aiko.dev/no-10x-engineer-needed/</id> <content src="https://aiko.dev/no-10x-engineer-needed/" /> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> </author> <summary>Finally, after years of contractually required abstinence from public speaking, my new talk is out. Abstract: This talk discusses how a good developer experience (design system, scaffolding tools, tech standards, …), combined with the right organisational structures and operating model, a lean team composition with a focus on autonomy, and an organisation that measures individual impact can...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>The most productive shell commands and command line tricks</title><link href="https://aiko.dev/shell-commands/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The most productive shell commands and command line tricks" /><published>2021-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</published> <updated>2024-11-17T17:37:11+08:00</updated> <id>https://aiko.dev/shell-commands/</id> <content src="https://aiko.dev/shell-commands/" /> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> </author> <summary>When developing software, no matter what technology you are working with there is no way around using the command line when you want to be a productive developer. This a list of my favorite and most used shell commands and tricks that I learned over the years. I’m sure you know some of them already so feel to skip the ones you know but others might bring you a productivity boost and lets you s...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>[Talk] Artificial Intelligence? - more like Artificial Stupidity!</title><link href="https://aiko.dev/artificial-stupidity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Talk] Artificial Intelligence? - more like Artificial Stupidity!" /><published>2020-06-13T00:00:00+08:00</published> <updated>2024-11-17T17:25:58+08:00</updated> <id>https://aiko.dev/artificial-stupidity/</id> <content src="https://aiko.dev/artificial-stupidity/" /> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> </author> <summary>Abstract: Nowadays “Artificial Intelligence” is everywhere! And rightly so, it does enable us to do really cool things, things we couldn’t even imagine doing just a decade ago. In fact, it sometimes just feels like magic. This ‘magic’ behind it is often powered by “Machine Learning”. But even “AI” has its limitations. I’ll show examples where “AI” and ML have failed (sometimes with horrib...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>Analysing IMDB TV series data aka How Wesley Crusher affects Star Trek episode ratings</title><link href="https://aiko.dev/imdb-episode-ranking-star-trek/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Analysing IMDB TV series data aka How Wesley Crusher affects Star Trek episode ratings" /><published>2020-02-10T00:00:00+08:00</published> <updated>2024-11-17T17:26:26+08:00</updated> <id>https://aiko.dev/imdb-episode-ranking-star-trek/</id> <content src="https://aiko.dev/imdb-episode-ranking-star-trek/" /> <author> <name>Aiko Klostermann</name> </author> <summary>Have you ever wondered how much influence a single actor has on the rating of a TV show’s episodes? This article will showcase you that you can analyse data from the internet movie database(IMDb) for this, using Star Trek The Next Generation as example series. Some time ago I found out that my partner had not yet watched Star Trek The Next Generation(or any Star Trek series for that mater 😱). ...</summary> </entry> </feed>
